Guide to the Kathryn Walker papers, ca.1955-1992
Walker, Kathryn papers, ca.1955-1992
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Kathryn Walker Papers, ca.1955-1992
23-3-2821
Kathryn Walker.
3 cubic ft.
Correspondence, publications, films, and a video.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence from Walker's academic career, pertaining especially to time management and other aspects of home economics. Includes two films and a video, "Whatcha Doin Mama?", concerning time use studies.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor emeritus, New York State College of Human Ecology at Cornell University.
Kathryn Walker earned both bachelor's and master's degrees in home economics from Pennsylvania State University in 1938 and 1945 respectively. She received her Ph.D. from Cornell in 1955 and that same year joined the faculty of the Department of Household Economics and Home Management as an Assistant Professor. Her research included family management of resources and management of the family's work time as a resource for work and leisure. In 1979 she retired and was named professor emeritus.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence from Walker's academic career, pertaining especially to time management and other aspects of home economics.
Includes two films and a video, "Whatcha Doin Mama?", concerning time use studies.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Walker, Kathryn.; New York State College of Human Ecology.
Titles:
Watcha Doin Mama?
Subjects:
Time management.; Home economics.
Form and Genre Terms:
Motion pictures (visual works).; Videotapes.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
The films Whatcha Doin' Mama Part 1 and Whatcha Doin' Mama Part 2 from this collection have been digitized and can be found on Cornell's Library Media Space website along with other Home Economics and related films.
CONTAINER LIST
- Articles written by or featuring Walker. In English, or translations in French, Swedish, and Finnish*, 1955-1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 14-15)
- Correspondence, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 16-17)
- Correspondence, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 18-20)
- Correspondence with written material, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
- Correspondence with written material, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 4-6)
- Correspondence with written material, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
- Correspondence with written material, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 9-12)
- Correspondence with written material, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 13-15)
- Correspondence with written material, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 16-19)
- Correspondence with written material, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 1-5)
- Correspondence with written material, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 6-8)
- Correspondence with written material, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
- Correspondence with written material, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 11-13)
- Correspondence with written material, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Correspondence with written material, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Correspondence with written material, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Correspondence with written material, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Correspondence with written material, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Correspondence with written material, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Correspondence with written material, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Correspondence with written material, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Correspondence with written material, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Correspondence with written material, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- 35mm slides: Work height and lifting (Box 3)
- 35mm slides: Time (Box 3)
- 35mm slides: New York State Kitchen (Box 3)
- Lantern Slides: Time planning (Box 3)
- "Whatcha Doin' Mama?" - Parts 1 and 2, c.1969; V-414 (Box 3)
  Click here to see a digitized version of Part 1
  Click here to see a digitized version of Part 2
- "Whatcha Doin' Mama?" - Parts 1 and 2. Copy from V-414, c.1969; DVD-1007 (Box 3)